Erica Hanson

Developer Relations Program Manager, South and South East Asia at Google

Summary

I've been at Google for over 10 years and worked across different areas of the business (sales, operations, engineering) and in different offices (Mountain View, San Francisco, London, Singapore).

I'm currently part of the engineering org on the Developer Relations team and work with startups and developers across Southeast Asia. I am also the global lead of the Google Business Group (GBG) program - we work with 168 communities of entrepreneurs across the world.

I enjoy public speaking and have been fortunate to be able to speak to thousands of developers and startups at many events across Southeast Asia.

Check out a couple videos of the programs I have managed in Indonesia:

- Interview on Metro TV news about our Launchpad Accelerator program: https://goo.gl/photos/rU7sYURnJQrfNHLi8
- Recap video of our Launchpad Accelerator press conference in Indonesia: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aRTSWXEsLI4&feature=youtu.be

Experience

Developer Relations Program Manager, Southeast Asia at Google

April 2014 - Present

Google Developer Relations Ecosystem Country Lead for Indonesia, Sri Lanka, Nepal, Brunei, Papua New Guinea, and Bhutan helping developers adopt the latest in Android, Web, and Design.

Lead the Google Developers Launchpad Week in Indonesia, which is a 5 day bootcamp for early stage startups. (Website: https://events.withgoogle.com/launchpad-week-jakarta/)

Lead for Indonesia's premier technical event focused on Google technology, the "Google Developers Summit."

Organized a 150 person summit for our community leaders from India, China, and Southeast Asia in Sri Lanka in 2014. These are community managers for the Google Developer Groups and Google Business Groups and also Google Developer Experts.

Global lead for the Google Business Group program, which includes 168 grassroots communities lead by passionate and inspiring community leaders with a goal of getting more entrepreneurs online and using Google technology to start and scale their businesses.

Project Manager, Sales Strategy & Operations, North & Central Europe at Google

January 2011 - April 2014 (3 years 3 months)

I worked on projects all with a goal of driving the efficiency and effectiveness of our sales organization across North and Central Europe. One core project was setting up the process of determining what leads are shown to our sales team in the CRM tool on a quarterly basis.

Program Manager, Emerging Markets Outreach at Google

October 2013 - December 2013 (2 months)

While on my Q4 rotation in Singapore, I lead the Women on the Web program for the Emerging Markets/ Engineering team. The goal of the program is to build a strong community of female entrepreneurs across Southeast Asia (and Pakistan) and provide them with the training and tools needed to grow their businesses online.

Agency Account Executive at Google

September 2006 - December 2010 (4 years 3 months)

Sales manager driving strategy and sales on \$xxM book of 30 SEM agencies with a 35.6% Y/Y growth

Manage a team of 5 people, spanning across 3 Google offices (SF, Boston, Hyderabad-India)

Use short-term and long-term business plans to strategically support agency portfolio and allocate resources efficiently; focus on scalable solutions

Deliver quarterly business reviews to agency C-levels to grow Google Share in Search, Display, YouTube, Mobile, and TV

Intern at Cohn & Wolfe

June 2005 - September 2005 (3 months)

Education

Stanford University

BA, Psychology, Communications, 2002 - 2006

Activities and Societies: - Stanford Undergraduate Psychology Association Peer Advisor - Starting scrumhalf for 3 out of the 4 years on the Stanford Women's Rugby Team (we won 2 national championships in 2005 and 2006).

Stanford University

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Psychology and Communications, 2002 - 2006

Erica Hanson

Developer Relations Program Manager, South and South East Asia at Google



Contact Erica on LinkedIn